<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Marine Lasbleis</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2020-05-25T00:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>New paper: exoplanets structure (Noack &amp; Lasbleis 2020)</title><link href="/exostructure.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-05-25T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-05-25T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Marine Lasbleis</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-05-25:/exostructure.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;New paper published in Astronomy \&amp;amp; Astrophysics&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dr. Noack and I published a new work in Geophysical Research Letters:&lt;a href="https://www.aanda.org/component/article?access=doi&amp;amp;doi=10.1051/0004-6361/202037723"&gt;Parameterisations of interior properties of rocky planets. An investigation of planets with Earth-like compositions but variable iron content &lt;/a&gt; (free access). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We describe and parametrize the internal structure and physical parameters of the different layers of terrestrial exoplanets (without large atmospheres). The parametrization is also available from the group of Dr. Noack in Berlin &lt;a href="http://geodyn-chic.de/tools"&gt;as a tool&lt;/a&gt;, and is also implemented in Python in a &lt;a href="https://gitlab.univ-nantes.fr/lasbleis-m/planetstructure"&gt;gitlab repository at Université de Nantes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="new"></category><category term="paper"></category><category term="publication"></category><category term="exoplanets"></category><category term="structure"></category><category term="msca"></category><category term="EU"></category></entry><entry><title>New paper: inner core compaction</title><link href="/compaction.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-01-05T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-01-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Marine Lasbleis</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-01-05:/compaction.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;New paper published in Geophysical Research Letters&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We published a new work in Geophysical Research Letters:&lt;a href="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2019GL085654"&gt;the fate of liquids trapped during the Earth's inner core growth&lt;/a&gt;. This is about compaction of a mushy inner core, and what we can learn about the supercooling hypothesis (delayed nucleation). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Arxiv version is still available &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1912.12258"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="new"></category><category term="paper"></category><category term="publication"></category><category term="compaction"></category><category term="inner core"></category><category term="msca"></category><category term="EU"></category></entry><entry><title>MSCA-IF</title><link href="/msca.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-08-19T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-19T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Marine Lasbleis</name></author><id>tag:None,2019-08-19:/msca.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I started my project InDyMag on March this year&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In March 2019, I started a new project and a new position. I am now officially a MSCA-IF Post doctoral fellow. More info on MSCA-IF (Marie Skłodowska-Curie Individual Fellowship) on the &lt;a href="https://ec.europa.eu/research/mariecurieactions/news/2019-msca-call-individual-fellowships-open_en"&gt;European Commission website (for this year call, for example)&lt;/a&gt;. This is an incredible opportunity for me, and the reason I came back to Europe last year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project InDyMag is about investigating the long term evolution of planetary cores, with a particular interest for the magnetic field. Basically, how a core evolves and crystallizes and the implications for predictions and observations of magnetic field. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for new results soon, and I will be talking at the &lt;a href="https://www.epsc-dps2019.eu/"&gt;EPSC-DPS&lt;/a&gt; meeting mid-September in Geneva!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="new"></category><category term="position"></category><category term="job"></category><category term="msca"></category><category term="EU"></category></entry><entry><title>AGU2018</title><link href="/agu2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-12-02T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-12-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Marine Lasbleis</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-12-02:/agu2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Two posters at AGU 2018&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Next week, it's AGU Fall meeting time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll be presenting two posters on inner core, one focus on the Earth, and a second one focus on exoplanets. I'll also be chairing the SEDI Core session on Thursday morning (starting 8am).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to stop me for a coffee or lunch!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DI43B-0022: Compaction of a mushy inner core : the fate of liquid trapped by fast growth. &lt;a href="https://agu.confex.com/agu/fm18/meetingapp.cgi/Paper/404813"&gt;abstract here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P31D-3737: Can Massive Rocky Exoplanets Have a Solid Inner Core?  &lt;a href="https://agu.confex.com/agu/fm18/meetingapp.cgi/Paper/390408"&gt;abstract here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DI41A &lt;a href="https://agu.confex.com/agu/fm18/meetingapp.cgi/Session/60339"&gt;talks&lt;/a&gt; and DI43B &lt;a href="https://agu.confex.com/agu/fm18/meetingapp.cgi/Session/49493"&gt;posters&lt;/a&gt;: Exploring the Earth’s Core: A Multidisciplinary Approach&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="agu"></category><category term="conference"></category><category term="poster"></category></entry><entry><title>Starting a new position</title><link href="/new-job.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-10T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-09-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Marine Lasbleis</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-09-10:/new-job.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I just started a post-doc at LPG!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This September, I moved from Japan to France, starting a new position at the Laboratoire de Planétologie et Géodynamique, in the wonderful city of Nantes, France. I will work 6 months on finishing up a couple of papers and projects with people from both Nantes and Tokyo, and then I'll start a Marie Curie Fellowship in the same institute!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm super excited by this new adventure, and looking forward to the discussions with my new colleagues here in Nantes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also means I'm back in Europe, so I'll be able to visit labs here more easily!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="new"></category><category term="position"></category><category term="job"></category></entry><entry><title>WPI Visit 2018</title><link href="/WPI-visit-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-15T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-07-15T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Marine Lasbleis</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-07-15:/WPI-visit-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;WPI visit on July 23-25&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;ELSI is part of the World Premier International Research Center Initiative (WPI) of the Ministry of Education, Culture, Sports, Science and Technology (MEXT.) in Japan. Every year or almost, all researchers and professors in ELSI are presenting their research to a WPI committee. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, I will be presenting my on-going research on the stratified layers in the Earth's core at this meeting!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="summer"></category><category term="2018"></category><category term="WPI"></category></entry><entry><title>Study of the Earth Deep Interior meeting 2018</title><link href="/sedi-2018-talk.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-01T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-07-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Marine Lasbleis</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-07-01:/sedi-2018-talk.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'll be at the SEDI meeting 2018 in Edmonton, Canada, in July.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'll be at the SEDI meeting 2018 in Edmonton, Canada, in July! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will present my last publication (GrowYourIC) and the last updates to compare seismic observations and geodynamical models for the inner core. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More info on the meeting on &lt;a href="https://sedi2018.sciencesconf.org/"&gt;their website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="conference"></category><category term="2018"></category></entry><entry><title>Summer 2018 in Tokyo</title><link href="/summer-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-01T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-07-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Marine Lasbleis</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-07-01:/summer-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Mathilde Kervazo, from Nantes, is joigning ELSI for the summer.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Starting mid July, Mathilde Kervazo will join ELSI for a month, to work with me on inner core dynamics. She then will go back to France and be a PhD student at the Laboratoire de Géodynamique et Planétologie in Nantes. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="summer"></category><category term="2018"></category><category term="students"></category></entry><entry><title>New website</title><link href="/new-website.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-14T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-06-14T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Marine Lasbleis</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-06-14:/new-website.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the first article on my new website!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the first article on my new website!&lt;br&gt;
I'll update this webpage to tell you more about my research interests and my academic news. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been reading a lot about building static pages. My old website was a single html page with css that I wrote myself (with things copied from other websites, trying to understand the basics of html). Since I'm using Python almost everyday, I thought that using a python-based thing would make more sense. At first, I followed a couple of tutorials for django, then decided it was too complicated for my need. But I may come back to it if I want to build a dynamical website with some python included... We'll see.&lt;br&gt;
I've been reading some other blogs, looking online for more info about pelican, such as &lt;a href="https://peterwittek.com/academic-website-with-pelican.html"&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://szhorvat.net/pelican/a-new-website-with-pelican.html"&gt;this other one&lt;/a&gt; and thinking about what I need and what can wait. Amongst the couple of things people are interested, there is bibtex... It's good to know that it's possible to use it to build nice bibliographies. However, I may wait until either writing longer blog posts with bibliography, or having more publications to present on my Research page! &lt;br&gt;
Oh, and with pelican, I can even add maths... 
$$ \int_0^x dx = x $$&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="new"></category></entry></feed>